Peter Tawfik

PERSONAL DATA

Full Name: Peter Atef Tawfik

Date of Birth: 9th of December 1983

Nationality: Egypt Marital Status: Married

Location: Shorouk City, Cairo, Egypt

CONTACT INFO

Mobile: 00201224580730
Phone: 0020226241888
Email: p.atef@hotmail.com
Website: www.peinstein.com

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/peinstein

LinkedIn: https://eg.linkedin.com/pub/peter-atef/45/876/337

Summary

More than 10 years' extensive experience in wide range of operating system administration, automation, monitoring, Mail/DNS/Application servers/Web tools/CMS administration and configurations, developing programming languages, scripting languages, database administration, network administration and configuration, web page authoring, web solutions, portals, backend solutions, APIs; business process development and technical process alignment with business goals using range of software methodologies. Also assumed multiple technical, strategic and leadership roles throughout my varied professional career.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oct 2016 to Present (3 months)

Front-End Developer Team Lead at Medaf Investment Cairo, Egypt.

Industry: Information Technology Services. Company Size: 11-50 employees

- Owning the front-end customization and integration with customers applications.
- Managing the delivery of the project releases on multiple environments.
- Expanding front-end capabilities to new platforms and technologies.
- Collaborating with Product Designers, Product Managers, and other Team Leaders to plan, nurture, and implement an efficient and effective development process.
- Delivering a complete front-end application
- Ensuring high performance
- Interaction with databases (mongo dB, MySQL, elastic search)
- Using programming language as React, Redux beside the html, Css, BOOTSTRAP
- Governing the whole user interface and experience
- Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the RESTful API

May 2016 to Oct 2019

Senior UI-Developer at AvidBeam Technology

(3 year and 6 months)

Cairo, Egypt.

Industry: Information Technology Services. Company Size: 11-50 employees

- Delivering a complete front-end application
- Ensuring high performance
- Writing tested and idiomatic JavaScript, HTML and CSS, BOOTSTRAP,
- Interaction with databases (mongo dB, MySQL, elastic search)
- Using programming language as Ruby on rails, React, Redux



- Governing the whole user interface and experience
- Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the RESTful API

Jan 2014 to May 2016

Team Leader Web Developer at JET

(2 years and 4 months)

Industry: Education. Company Size: 11-50 employees

- Collaborates effectively with creative team and web designers during the creative process.
- Provides technical leadership and assumes overall accountability for a successful implementation phase on all client projects. Oversees employee, freelance web developers and partner web developers, ensures technical solutions are properly architected and specified, and reviews all code for quality assurance purposes.
- In partnership with technical leads, helps set direction for our technology practice.
- building front-end, and back-end websites, from the PSD to live, with its backend
- building Online Applications like attendance systems, stock management systems, proposal systems, quotation and finance system

Oct 2012 to Dec 2013

Senior Web Developer at smart wedding guide

(1 year and 2 months)

Cairo, Egypt.

Cairo, Egypt.

Industry: Marketing and Advertising. Company Size: 11-50 employees

- Collaborates effectively with creative team and web designers during the creative process.
- Provides technical leadership and assumes overall accountability for a successful implementation phase on all client projects. Oversees employee, freelance web developers and partner web developers, ensures technical solutions are properly architected and specified, and reviews all code for quality assurance purposes.
- In partnership with technical leads, helps set direction for our technology practice.
- · building front-end, and back-end websites, from the PSD to live, with its backend
- building Online Applications like attendance systems, stock management systems, proposal Systems, quotation and finance system

Jul 2011 to Sep 2012

Senior web developer at CANN7

(1 year and 2 months)

Cairo, Egypt.

Industry: Information Technology Services. Company Size: 11-50 employees

- Build and kick-start new services, in terms of technicality, processes, contracts and support model.
- Slicing psd to html and css, php, mysql for the most of the Sites Required

Nov 2007 to Jun 2011

Senior Web Developer at Graphicano

(3 years and 7 months)

Cairo, Egypt.

Industry: Information Technology Services. Company Size: 1-10 employees

- Collaborates effectively with creative team and web designers during the creative process.
- Provides technical leadership and assumes overall accountability for a successful implementation phase on all client projects. Oversees employee, freelance web developers and partner web developers, ensures technical solutions are properly architected and specified, and reviews all code for quality assurance purposes.
- In partnership with technical leads, helps set direction for our technology practice.
- building front-end, and back-end websites, from the PSD to live, with its backend
- building Online Applications like attendance systems, stock management systems, proposal Systems, quotation and finance system
- Building websites starting from the psd
- Building CMS and improving the techniques used to make it user friendly and having most of features required to most of the websites
- · building booking systems for hotels

EDUCATION

Ain Shams University, Egypt. Studied Subjects: computer system engineer

2002 Thanaweya Amma, Frere Patriacal college, Egypt.

Some Online Projects

- http://www.stmichaelinc.com
- http://peinstein.com/cam
- http://techwaytrading.com/
- http://egyphar.net/
- http://drashrafharris.com/
- http://hec-eg.com/

Some Online Application

- Development of a CMS for each project done, having all the features the website need from editing contents, adding photos, videos, in a very user friendly way
- Making Attendance System to help managements to monitor their employee's attendance
- BUDGET Application, so user can monitor his/her monthly requirements and savings

ACHIEVEMENTS

Kindly see some of my online projects on www.facebook.com/peinstein Thanks and best regards.

LANGUAGES

Arabic and English: Fluent.

French: Intermediate.

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Advanced in HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jquery and AJAX, React, Redux, Bootstrap

Intermediate in less, scss, git, MongoDB, Docker, ruby, rails, json, API and elastic search.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Advanced in html, css, php, mysql, javascript, ajax, jquery, web devlopment, front-end and back-end, cpanel, bootstrap, css3, html5

SKILLS, Interests and Activities

Leader, Planner, Hard worker, Interactive, Team Player, Follow new technologies and best practices in software development and enterprises.